<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
  <title><![CDATA[Safe Flights Blog]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[All your know about flight safety]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog//"/>
  <updated>2015-11-13T09:13:08.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog//</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Safe Flights]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[3 Steps to Overcoming Your Fear of Flying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/11/13/8-Steps-to-Overcoming-Your-Fear-of-Flying/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/11/13/8-Steps-to-Overcoming-Your-Fear-of-Flying/</id>
    <published>2015-11-13T10:29:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-11-13T09:13:08.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ge4ZU5i.jpg?1" alt="3 Steps to Overcoming Fear of Flying"></p>
<p>If you have a fear of flying, you are not alone. Did you know that at least one out of every six adults are afraid to fly? Actually, even 35 percent of all airline crews, flight attendants and poliots have fear of flying, too. But we will help you to overcome the fear by following these five steps.<br><a id="more"></a> </p>
<h2 id="1-_Recognise_the_source_of_the_fear">1. Recognise the source of the fear</h2><p>We know that you are afraid of falling! When you are so up on high in the air, It’s natural to think you may fall because we are so used to stand on something solid, let us tell you something to start off, air travel is actually the second-safest mode of mass transportation in the world, only second to the escalator and elevator. Your chances of being involved in an aircraft accident are approximately 1 in 11 million. Your chances of being killed in an automobile accident are 1 in 5000, so the most dangerous part of your flight will actually be the drive to the airport, funny right?</p>
<h2 id="2-_Board_a_airplane_with_knowledge">2. Board a airplane with knowledge</h2><p>People will get terrified when they don’t know what they are dealing with - another human nature, so don’t be ashamed if you do. When it comes to the air travel, if you are not familiar with how the airplane works, such as why it can fly in the sky? why it sometimes vibrates heavily, and what is the  noise inside the plane… you will get anxious pretty quickly about some situations which are actually normal .. so do some research at home, or when you are waiting for the boarding, it will make your trip less worried.</p>
<h2 id="3-_Choose_a_safer_airline">3. Choose a safer airline</h2><p>It is important to choose a safe airline even you have no fear of flying. The definition of a safe airline majorly consists of - Advanced airplane model, and solid company operation. Therefor airline’s accidents record will be the best reference for you. A safe airline like Qatar Airways, which only has 5 aviation accidents throughout  the history( <em>Link</em> <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Qatar%20Airways"><strong>Aviation Accidents Records of Qatar</strong></a>), ), means they manage their planes and services really well. According to <a href="http://www.worldairlineawards.com/awards/world_airline_rating.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Skytrax World Airline Awards</a>, Qatar Airways is the top airline in 2015.</p>
<p>Visit our website for more info about all the safe airlines in the world.</p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Twitter">Follow Us In Twitter</h5><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SafeFlights_" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Twitter Page Link</a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page Link</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ge4ZU5i.jpg?1" alt="3 Steps to Overcoming Fear of Flying"></p>
<p>If you have a fear of flying, you are not alone. Did you know that at least one out of every six adults are afraid to fly? Actually, even 35 percent of all airline crews, flight attendants and poliots have fear of flying, too. But we will help you to overcome the fear by following these five steps.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/undefined/"/>
    
      <category term="Safe, Rondoctor" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Safe-Rondoctor/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Delta Difference]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/10/18/Delta-s-pros-and-cons/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/10/18/Delta-s-pros-and-cons/</id>
    <published>2015-10-18T11:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-26T05:04:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://livnews.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/richard_anderson_delta-air-lines-ceo.jpg" alt="Delta"></p>
<p>It takes Delta 86 years to grow from a crop-dusting operation to a global airline serving more than 300 destinations on six continents. What makes this airline so special? We are intended to use a full article to analyze and summarize the good and the not-that-great factors of Delta as well as other airlines we are going to write about in the following articles , and hoping that this could really benefit you choosing the best and safest flight to your budget.</p>
<a id="more"></a> 
<p>Our subject “Delta Difference” comes from one of the famous quotes of the founder Collett E. Woolman and it is famous for a lot of reasons. </p>
<p>Major Strengths:</p>
<ol>
<li>World’s largest airline in terms of fleet number and passengers carried, it also has an unbeatably extensive route network and frequencies especially within North America.</li>
<li>Delta is the only U.S. carrier to offer personal, on demand entertainment at every seat on all long-haul, and international flights along with various other unqiue in-flight experiences.</li>
<li>Ranked within Top 3 of all “Most punctual airline” listing.</li>
<li>Delta stands high both on the Consumer Warning Network’s list and ABC News’s list for safety ranking: second and fifth, respectively.</li>
</ol>
<p>“Largest” could be defined by so many ways, and we are not talking about the profits, numbers of the emolyees here. Delta is the largest by assets, market capitalization, fleet number and passengers carried, it operates more than 5,000 flights daily which connect to almost everywhere that you want to go, do you know that Delta even has an exclusive airport only runs their own planes near the yellowstone?</p>
<p>Delta is incredibly innovative on boosting passengers’ experiences, in every way. To start with, its app is the best among all other airlines, you can not only buy tickets, select seats, add extra services, check-in through the app, but also use the bar code instead of printed tickets to board which is a big time-saver. There are countless features that Delta came up with just to suprise us, such as in-flight free wifi (which is popular in other airlines now but was orginally offered by Delta first, and Delta still has more planes with wifi than all other competitors), leather seats!! (My and everyone’s favourite part!), generally bigger leg room specially in coach cabin (this comes with bigger airplanes which Delta has been agressively updating to), the personal, on demand entertainment on long-haul or international flights as we mentioned above (and Safe flights just dscovered that you can use other devices to play all the movies once  you connect to the wifi, can I love you more Delta? ). And one thing we have to mention here, its safety video! Each safety video that Delta released always went viral on the internet, check out our blog and find out why :-)   <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/2015/09/24/The-Best-Airline-Safety-Video-in-2015/#more">Click here</a><br>This video alone is enough to prove how much heart that Delta has put in just to make us smile.</p>
<p>When it comes to safety, according to our Safe Flights Database, Delta only has 58 aviation accidents throughout the history, it boasts only 0.17 fatalities per million miles traveled which is low, very low…</p>
<p>People are complaining:</p>
<ol>
<li>Delta charges for the second checked bag.</li>
<li>Delta miles can be hard to use.</li>
</ol>
<p>That’s it, two short lists of compaints and they are straight forward so we won’t extend them, We sorted through the internet, there really aren’t many major weakness mentioned about this airline, and it seems that comparing to the strengths, the above complaints are not really the obstacles keep people from flying with it at all.</p>
<p>As long as we want to throw dagger at Delta, but to be realistic, it truly is a solid operation, and constantly changing to the market, to the better service and higher customer satisfaction. With all those unconventional stratgies taken and been in action, we have reasons to believe Delta is a quality choice.</p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights-Flight_Safety_Guide_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights-Flight Safety Guide App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Twitter">Follow Us In Twitter</h5><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SafeFlights_" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Twitter Page Link</a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page Link</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://livnews.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/richard_anderson_delta-air-lines-ceo.jpg" alt="Delta"></p>
<p>It takes Delta 86 years to grow from a crop-dusting operation to a global airline serving more than 300 destinations on six continents. What makes this airline so special? We are intended to use a full article to analyze and summarize the good and the not-that-great factors of Delta as well as other airlines we are going to write about in the following articles , and hoping that this could really benefit you choosing the best and safest flight to your budget.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Delta" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Delta/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Strategy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Best Flight Safety Video in 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/09/24/The-Best-Airline-Safety-Video-in-2015/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/09/24/The-Best-Airline-Safety-Video-in-2015/</id>
    <published>2015-09-24T04:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-26T05:04:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://media.bizj.us/view/img/6655602/screen-shot-2015-08-07-at-104340-am*750xx1163-654-55-0.png" alt="Delta&#39;s Flight Safety Video"><br>Most of the flight safety videos are boring, let’s just admit it…nobody could have the patience to watch the scripted and dull videos over and over again!</p>
<p>But we need to be reminded by these important messages every time we are on a plane, for obvious reasons. So can these videos be better? can they just hold our attention a little longer and while we are concentrated, tell us what we can do in an emergency? Delta is here to tell you, they can!  </p>
<a id="more"></a> 
<h1 id="Delta’s_Flight_Safety_Video">Delta’s Flight Safety Video</h1><p>Delta makes the flight safety videos so interesting. We could see when the pretty flight attendant demostrating the safety rules, there are a lot of funny scenes appear on the screen, such as a giant squirrel(dressed up by a person) fitting a nut into the overhead bin, which is to remind you doing the same thing, or the Moses parting the aisles, which is also to remind you to sit down. So funny! So creative! So effective! And from our experiences, everybody is watching and laughing through the whole video, instead of just doing their own thing.</p>
<p>Salute to Delta! You did a good job!</p>
<div class="video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/kfFHn6DxvEg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Twitter">Follow Us In Twitter</h5><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SafeFlights_" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Twitter Page Link</a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page Link</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://media.bizj.us/view/img/6655602/screen-shot-2015-08-07-at-104340-am*750xx1163-654-55-0.png" alt="Delta&#39;s Flight Safety Video"><br>Most of the flight safety videos are boring, let’s just admit it…nobody could have the patience to watch the scripted and dull videos over and over again!</p>
<p>But we need to be reminded by these important messages every time we are on a plane, for obvious reasons. So can these videos be better? can they just hold our attention a little longer and while we are concentrated, tell us what we can do in an emergency? Delta is here to tell you, they can!  </p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Flight, Safety, Funny" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Flight-Safety-Funny/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Turbulence on Hainan Airlines leads to 30 Chinese Injuries]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/17/Keep-Belt-Fastend-Turbulence-on-Hainan-Airlines-leads-to-30-Chinese-injuries/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/17/Keep-Belt-Fastend-Turbulence-on-Hainan-Airlines-leads-to-30-Chinese-injuries/</id>
    <published>2015-08-17T04:58:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-26T05:04:51.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/20150811-wld-hainan-1.jpg" alt="HU7148 Photo: Thepaper.cn"></p>
<p>On Aug 11th, A flight of <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Hainan%20Airlines">Hainan Airlines</a>, HU7148, a <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/a320">Airbus A330-200</a>, encountered severe turbulence during the flight from Chengdu airport to Beijing, China, the plane was jolted twice and descending through about 4200 meters, The crew continued for a safe landing in Beijing about 17 minutes later, but the incident still caused total 30 Chinese passengers and crew members injured.</p>
<a id="more"></a> 
<h2 id="Terrifying_Experience">Terrifying Experience</h2><p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/U10856P1T1D32191918F23DT20150811184004.jpg" alt="Damaged Cabin Photo: Weibo"></p>
<p>“It was the strongest shaking I have ever had in my life. I see people behind me having their heads knocked. The blood and sobs really scared me “, One passenger posted on weibo.</p>
<p>“I was thrown upwards and hit the ceiling before I had the time to fasten my seatbelt”, another passenger wrote.</p>
<p>Some injuries, surprisingly, are simply from the reason that people not belted into their seats! They were lifted off and impacted the ceiling of the aircraft before coming down again, like the passengers wrote above.</p>
<h2 id="Keep_Your_Seat_Belt_Fastened">Keep Your Seat Belt Fastened</h2><p>Turbulence is the leading cause of injuries to airline passengers and flight attendants in non-fatal plane accidents according to <a href="https://www.faa.gov/passengers/fly_safe/turbulence/" target="_blank" rel="external">FAA website</a>. The turbulence that HU7148 experienced was an in-flight turbulence, which happens very often.</p>
<p>Today, even the best airplane can not 100% detect clear-air turbulence, especially mountain wave turbulence, which is formed by specific air flows around the mountains. So keep in mind to keep your seat belts fastened during the flight! You will never know what will happen in next second.</p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/20150811-wld-hainan-1.jpg" alt="HU7148 Photo: Thepaper.cn"></p>
<p>On Aug 11th, A flight of <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Hainan%20Airlines">Hainan Airlines</a>, HU7148, a <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/a320">Airbus A330-200</a>, encountered severe turbulence during the flight from Chengdu airport to Beijing, China, the plane was jolted twice and descending through about 4200 meters, The crew continued for a safe landing in Beijing about 17 minutes later, but the incident still caused total 30 Chinese passengers and crew members injured.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel, Flight, Safety, Airbus, 320, Tao Yan" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Travel-Flight-Safety-Airbus-320-Tao-Yan/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Indonesian TGN267 carrying 54 people missing in Papua]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/16/indonesian-tgn267-carrying-54-people-missing-in-papua/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/16/indonesian-tgn267-carrying-54-people-missing-in-papua/</id>
    <published>2015-08-16T12:00:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-25T04:13:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="/blog/2015/08/16/indonesian-tgn267-carrying-54-people-missing-in-papua/983088-a9f41668-4403-11e5-895e-ea44465fec65.jpg" alt="Trigana Air" title="Trigana Air">
<p>An Indonesian aircraft, flight TGN267, is missing in Papua. This plane is carrying 44 adults, five children and five crew. After it left Sentani airport about half an hour, it disappeared. The last record showed it was in a very remote jungle area.<br><a id="more"></a><br>According to spokesman J.A. Barata, the weather is very bad now. But he had no idea what happened to this plane.</p>
<p>Trigana Air is a small airline. It established in 1991 and provides domestic services in Indonesia. Trigana Air has been on the European Union blacklist of banned carriers since 2007.</p>
<h3 id="1_Flight_Accident_of_ATR_42-300">1 Flight Accident of ATR 42-300</h3><p>Flight TGN267 was a ATR 42-300 plane, which has only one flight accident in our database.<br><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/ATR%2042-300" target="_blank">ATR 42-300 Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Twitter">Follow Us In Twitter</h5><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SafeFlights_" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Twitter Page Link</a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page Link</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="/blog/2015/08/16/indonesian-tgn267-carrying-54-people-missing-in-papua/983088-a9f41668-4403-11e5-895e-ea44465fec65.jpg" alt="Trigana Air" title="Trigana Air">
<p>An Indonesian aircraft, flight TGN267, is missing in Papua. This plane is carrying 44 adults, five children and five crew. After it left Sentani airport about half an hour, it disappeared. The last record showed it was in a very remote jungle area.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel, Flight, Safety, Accidents, Dexter" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Travel-Flight-Safety-Accidents-Dexter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[What We Need to Do Next, After Debris Is Determined From MH370]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/06/what-we-need-to-do-next-after-debris-is-determined-from-MH370/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/06/what-we-need-to-do-next-after-debris-is-determined-from-MH370/</id>
    <published>2015-08-06T01:51:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-25T04:13:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/Flight-MH370.jpg" alt="MH370"></p>
<p>On Thursday,  Malaysian PWrime Minister confirmed that plane debris found on the Reunion Island in the Indian Ocean belongs to missing Flight MH370. It is a great breakthrough in solving one of aviation’s greatest mysteries.</p>
<p>In the statement, Malaysian Prime Minister said “Today, 515 days since the plane disappeared, it is with a heavy heart that I must tell you that an international team of experts have conclusively confirmed that the aircraft debris found on Reunion Island is indeed from MH370,”<br><a id="more"></a> </p>
<h2 id="What_We_Need_to_Do_Next">What We Need to Do Next</h2><p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/CurrentsMH370.gif" alt="Indian Ocean Drift"><br>According to this map, we can find sea currents were pushing the wing part almost 4000 kilometres from previous seach area. It will become very hard for searching team to continue their work in previous area. Since there were no further wreckage found on the island, we can guess that the entire plane was submerged in the ocean. However, MH370 is an important alerm that make people and airline to think more about flight safety. In the MH370’s accident, Malaysian Airline’s pool management is the main cause. If we want less flight accidents appear in the furture, the only thing we need to do is spending more time and money on flight safety and improving management, not cheap ticket.</p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a><br><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/Flight-MH370.jpg" alt="MH370"></p>
<p>On Thursday,  Malaysian PWrime Minister confirmed that plane debris found on the Reunion Island in the Indian Ocean belongs to missing Flight MH370. It is a great breakthrough in solving one of aviation’s greatest mysteries.</p>
<p>In the statement, Malaysian Prime Minister said “Today, 515 days since the plane disappeared, it is with a heavy heart that I must tell you that an international team of experts have conclusively confirmed that the aircraft debris found on Reunion Island is indeed from MH370,”<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel, Flight, Safety, Boeing, 777, MH370, Dexter" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Travel-Flight-Safety-Boeing-777-MH370-Dexter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Is Boeing 777 safe?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/01/is-boeing-777-safe/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/08/01/is-boeing-777-safe/</id>
    <published>2015-08-01T02:41:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-25T04:13:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/c7/Boeing_777_above_clouds,_crop.jpg" alt="Boeing 777"></p>
<h2 id="Is_the_Boeing_777_aricraft_safe?">Is the Boeing 777 aricraft safe?</h2><p>In the last week, accident investigators determined the piece of wreckage found on shore in Saint-Andre, Reunion Island, was part of a Boeing 777 aircraft, which may belong to the missing Malaysia Airline Flight MH370. While this unexpected news brings up the hope finding the ultimate reason of this mysterious air crash, it also brings out the question to us again - How safe Boeing 777, as the most famous aircraft type in the world could be? In the past year, Boeing 777 had two world-awakening flight accidents which caused hundreds of people lost their lives. One of which, the missing MH370, has became the recent world’s greatest aviation mystery. We have no idea how and where this Boeing 777 disappeared in the Indian Ocean. However, even after these two deadly accidents, Boeing 777’s aviation record is still among the best in aviation history.<br><a id="more"></a> </p>
<h3 id="13_Flight_Accidents_of_Boeing_777">13 Flight Accidents of Boeing 777</h3><p>In <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a>‘ database,ever since Boeing 777  entered service in June 1995, there have been <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/Boeing%20777"><strong>13</strong></a>  accidents of Boeing 777, 5 of them have led to the total destruction of the aircraft, and MH370 is the only one of this type has vanished over the sea.</p>
<p>The first Boeing 777 hull loss was a British Airways jet on January 17, 2008 which landed 1,000 feet short of the runway. The fuel-oil heat exchanger of its engines are clogged by ice crystals in the fuel.</p>
<p>The second hull loss was in July 2011 when an Egypt Air jet caught fire at Cairo international Airport. The electrical fault or short circuit in oxygen system was the reason caused the fire.</p>
<p>The third was in July 2013 when a Boeing 777 of Asiana Airways crashed at San Francisco International Airport. Its landing gear and tail struck the seawall of San Francisco Bay.</p>
<p>The last two were MH370 and MH17. MH17 was shot down over the Russian Ukrainian border in July 2014.</p>
<h3 id="Safest_Wide-body_Commercial_Airliner">Safest Wide-body Commercial Airliner</h3><p><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/flightBlog/boeing-accident-stats.jpg" alt="A screenshot from the 2012 Boeing Annual Summary of Commercial Jet Airplane Accidents."></p>
<p>According to a chart published by Boeing in its <a href="http://www.boeing.com/resources/boeingdotcom/company/about_bca/pdf/statsum.pdf" target="_blank" rel="external">airline accidents report</a>, Boeing 777 was the safest wide-body commercial airliner in longtime service before any fatal accident. It only has 0.29 total hull loss per million departures. Today’s 777 operators still enjoy a 99.3 percent dispatch reliability rate, which Boeing calls “the highest amongst all twin-aisle airplanes in service today.”</p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a><br><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/c7/Boeing_777_above_clouds,_crop.jpg" alt="Boeing 777"></p>
<h2 id="Is_the_Boeing_777_aricraft_safe?">Is the Boeing 777 aricraft safe?</h2><p>In the last week, accident investigators determined the piece of wreckage found on shore in Saint-Andre, Reunion Island, was part of a Boeing 777 aircraft, which may belong to the missing Malaysia Airline Flight MH370. While this unexpected news brings up the hope finding the ultimate reason of this mysterious air crash, it also brings out the question to us again - How safe Boeing 777, as the most famous aircraft type in the world could be? In the past year, Boeing 777 had two world-awakening flight accidents which caused hundreds of people lost their lives. One of which, the missing MH370, has became the recent world’s greatest aviation mystery. We have no idea how and where this Boeing 777 disappeared in the Indian Ocean. However, even after these two deadly accidents, Boeing 777’s aviation record is still among the best in aviation history.<br>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel, Flight, Safety, Boeing, 777, b777, Dexter" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Travel-Flight-Safety-Boeing-777-b777-Dexter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Why Boeing 747 Crashed in Afghanistan?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/07/21/why-boeing-747-crash/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/07/21/why-boeing-747-crash/</id>
    <published>2015-07-21T00:57:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-25T04:13:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.aviationfigure.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/13-Things-you-didnt-know-about-the-Boeing-747.jpg" alt="Boeing 747"></p>
<h2 id="What_Causes_Boeing_747_Cargo_Crashed_in_Afghanistan?">What Causes Boeing 747 Cargo Crashed in Afghanistan?</h2><p>On April the 29th in 2013, a tragical flight accident had occurred in Afghanistan. A <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/Boeing%20747-428BCF"><strong>Boeing 747-400BCF</strong></a> cargo plane lost its control and crashed when taking off from Bagram Air Base. Seven crew members in the plane got killed immediately. This plane is operated by National Air Cargo.</p>
<a id="more"></a> 
<h4 id="Shocking_Video_of_Boeing_747_Cargo_Accident:">Shocking Video of Boeing 747 Cargo Accident:</h4><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-MB9JDBe4wA" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/-MB9JDBe4wA/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Boeing 747 Cargo Crash Video"></a></p>
<h3 id="119_Flight_Accidents_of_Boeing_747">119 Flight Accidents of Boeing 747</h3><p>In <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a>‘s database, there are <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/Boeing%20747"><strong>120</strong></a> accidents in record during the last ten years for Boeing 747 aircraft, and 3 of them are serious accidents with fatalities, which were all caused by loss of control. However, considering the fact that there are more than 1000 Boeing 747 currently busy in service, 3 is still a safe number.</p>
<h3 id="Improperly_Restrained_Cargo_Caused_Boeing_747_Crash">Improperly Restrained Cargo Caused Boeing 747 Crash</h3><p>People may wonder why plane in this safe kind would crash in such a shocking way. According to the NTSB(National Transportation Safety Board), this plane was carrying five mine-resistant ambush-protected (MRAP) vehicles, the crash occurred when at least one of the vehicles broke loose and moving very quickly toward the rear end during the takeoff, the key hydraulic systems were damaged and the horizontal stabilizer components failed to make response to the balance change, which made the freighter impossible to take control.</p>
<h3 id="How_Heavy_is_the_MRAP">How Heavy is the MRAP</h3><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/FPCougar.jpg/1024px-FPCougar.jpg" alt="MRAP"><br>Mine-Resistant Ambush-Rrotected (MRAP) vehicles are for military use and very heavy comparing with other regular cars. It weights close to 18 tons each. MRAP is designed for protecting the cars from improvised explosive device (IED) attack. A variant of the Humvee’s IED defeating Frag Kit 6 armor were installed on each vehicle, so when it is shifting so quickly in the plane, almost nothing can be done to handle the situation.</p>
<h3 id="Safe_Flights’s_quote">Safe Flights’s quote</h3><p>A lot of times, severe flight accidents were caused not by the quality of the aircraft, but the airline management or  unexpected situation such as this boeing 747 crash. </p>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external">Link</a><br><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.aviationfigure.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/13-Things-you-didnt-know-about-the-Boeing-747.jpg" alt="Boeing 747"></p>
<h2 id="What_Causes_Boeing_747_Cargo_Crashed_in_Afghanistan?">What Causes Boeing 747 Cargo Crashed in Afghanistan?</h2><p>On April the 29th in 2013, a tragical flight accident had occurred in Afghanistan. A <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/aircraft/Boeing%20747-428BCF"><strong>Boeing 747-400BCF</strong></a> cargo plane lost its control and crashed when taking off from Bagram Air Base. Seven crew members in the plane got killed immediately. This plane is operated by National Air Cargo.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Boeing, 747, Flight, Accidents, Tao Yan, Dexter" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Boeing-747-Flight-Accidents-Tao-Yan-Dexter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The World's 5 Safest Airlines for 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/07/16/five-safest-airlines-2015/"/>
    <id>http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/2015/07/16/five-safest-airlines-2015/</id>
    <published>2015-07-16T08:33:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-25T04:13:02.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.nationalairlines.com/css/images/nationalairlines_3.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="5_Safest_And_Best_Airlines_In_The_World">5 Safest And Best Airlines In The World</h2><p>If you are flying at 38,000 ft high, what is you most concern about. Drink, food or flight attendants? Nuh, not those for sure. But are you afraid of falling from the sky, oh Yes! Only when flights have landed on solid ground, you can feel totally rest assured and have your wonderful trip started. Today, <em><strong><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a> </strong></em> will unveiled the world top 5 safest and best airlines for you, dear travelers! Today, We, <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a> is the world’s best flight accidents search engine, we just launched in this year.</p>
<a id="more"></a> 
<p>Ok, back to the topic, this year’s top airline goes to…..<br>Qatar Airways! The other four are Emirates, Cathay Pacific Airways, Singapore Airlines and Qantas Airways.</p>
<h2 id="1-_Qatar_Airways">1. Qatar Airways</h2><p><img src="http://www.lowcostholidays.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/flightsinternationaluk.co_.uk_.jpg" alt="Qatar Airways"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Total Accidents: 3</strong> </li>
<li><p><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Qatar%20Airways" target="_blank">Qatar Airways Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Safe Flights says:</strong> Qatar has no casualties records! And it has the best air-travel service in this world, it will be a really enjoyable flying experience if you choose this airline.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Skytrax says: </strong> Qatar Airways also achieved success in the Best Business Class Seat category finishing in the top spot for the first time. It is probably no coincidence that this award has coincided with the introduction of the A380 and A350 aircraft into the QR fleet - survey respondents indicated that these latest seating designs have set new benchmark standards of comfort, space and privacy. </p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2-_Emirates">2. Emirates</h2><p><img src="http://www.aspireaviation.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Image-1-An-Emirates-Boeing-777-300-ER-aircraft.jpg" alt="Emirates"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Total Accidents: 4</strong> </li>
<li><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Emirates" target="_blank">Emirates Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></li>
<li><p><strong>Safe Flights says:</strong>  Emirates has achieved a great flight records during last 30 years. The last flight accident which caused 4 fatalities was in 1976. Choosing Emirates is a smart choice.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Skytrax says: </strong> Emirates retained their stranglehold on the World’s Best Inflight Entertainment awards at the 2015 Skytrax World Airline Awards in Paris. Finishing ahead of Qatar Airways in second place and Singapore Airlines in third, EK continues to have the edge over its closest global competitors despite continued hardware and programming improvements by carriers across the industry. Emirates secured the award for Best First Class Comfort Amenities ahead of local rival Etihad Airways and Singapore Airlines. At the top-end of the industry this is a very competitive category - particularly when assessing the quality levels between the top-5 airlines.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3-_Cathay_Pacific_Airways">3. Cathay Pacific Airways</h2><p><img src="http://downloads.cathaypacific.com/cx/aboutus/sd/2012/images/home/img_banner_1.jpg" alt="Cathay Pacific Airways"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Total Accidents: 8</strong> </li>
<li><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Cathay%20Pacific" target="_blank">Cathay Pacific Airways Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></li>
<li><p><strong>Safe Flights says:</strong> Cathay Pacific is the largest airline of Hong Kong, In the last 40 years, Cathay Pacific Airways did not have any serious flight accidents. They are able to guarantee that you can have a safe and nice air trip across the whole world. If you are traveling from Asia, Cathay Pacific Airways will be the best choice.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Skytrax says: </strong> Cathay Pacific achieved success by winning the Best Airline Transpacific for the third time at the 2015 Skytrax World Airline Awards in Paris. This was the airlines third success in this category having previously triumphed in 2011 and 2013. South Korea’s Asiana Airlines secured second position, with ANA All Nippon Airways achieving third place.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="4-_Singapore_Airlines">4. Singapore Airlines</h2><p><img src="http://flyawaysimulation.com/images/downloadshots/2146-sing-sdbzip-18-sin3.jpg" alt="Singapore Airlines"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Total Accidents: 10</strong> </li>
<li><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Singapore%20Airlines" target="_blank">Singapore Airlines Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></li>
<li><p><strong>Safe Flights says:</strong>  Singapore Airlines only has one serious accident back in 2000, which caused 83 fatalities. However, they have a very steady flight safety performance in history. Comparing with other airlines, they offer a better price with safe flight, if you have budget, this airline is a good start.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Skytrax says: </strong>  The Changi based flag carrier finished second in the global survey ranking edging out regional rival (and 2014 winner) Cathay Pacific Airways and ANA All Nippon Airways in the Asia region category. Singapore Airlines also achieved success at the front end of the aircraft with highly sought after World’s Best Business Class leading Qatar Airways and Cathay Pacific in second and third place.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="5-_Qantas_Airways">5. Qantas Airways</h2><p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/38/Qantas_A380-800_VH-OQD_SIN_2011-2-5.png" alt="Qantas Airways"></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Total Accidents: 13</strong>  </li>
<li><em><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/#!/search/airline/Qantas" target="_blank">Qantas Flight Accidents Summary Link</a></em></li>
<li><p><strong>Safe Flights says:</strong>  Qantas was founded in 1920, they are renowned by perfect aviation records in this industry. Definitely the first choice to make, when you plan to have a trip.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Skytrax says: </strong> Australia’s Qantas Airways had a successful year at the 2015 Skytrax World Airline Awards winning the Best Airline in Australia/Pacific award for the third consecutive year. Qantas also secured another top prize for the Best Business Class Comfort Amenities ahead of Qatar Airways and China’s Hainan Airlines with customers recognising the significant product upgrades made by QF in the last 2-years.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="Download_Our_Safe_Flights_App_On_Apple_Store">Download Our Safe Flights  App On Apple Store</h5><p>For more information, You can download our app on App Store. <a href="\https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4">Link</a><br><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/hk/app/flight-accidents/id998433297?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://www.safetyflights.com/images/ios-app.png" alt="Safe Flights App"></a></p>
<h5 id="Follow_Us_In_Facebook">Follow Us In Facebook</h5><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlightSafetyIsWhatWeCare?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="external">Safe Flights Facebook Page</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.nationalairlines.com/css/images/nationalairlines_3.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="5_Safest_And_Best_Airlines_In_The_World">5 Safest And Best Airlines In The World</h2><p>If you are flying at 38,000 ft high, what is you most concern about. Drink, food or flight attendants? Nuh, not those for sure. But are you afraid of falling from the sky, oh Yes! Only when flights have landed on solid ground, you can feel totally rest assured and have your wonderful trip started. Today, <em><strong><a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a> </strong></em> will unveiled the world top 5 safest and best airlines for you, dear travelers! Today, We, <a href="http://www.safetyflights.com/">Safe Flights</a> is the world’s best flight accidents search engine, we just launched in this year.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Travel, Flight, Safety, Tao Yan, Dexter" scheme="http://www.safetyflights.com/blog/blog/tags/Travel-Flight-Safety-Tao-Yan-Dexter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>